Sorry, beard's getting in my eyeball.
Ho ho ho. Merry Christmas everyone and
welcome to the holiday special Tik Tok
review video. I know it hasn't been that
long since we last did it, but this
feels like a tradition now to do a
Christmas time Tik Tok review video. And
I got a lot of requests to pull out the
old Santa costume. So, here you go. I
hope you're happy because because this
thing's hot. Beard's definitely gonna
come off soon. You can't you can't even
tell if I'm talking. You know the drill.
Your boy Santa is a registered portfolio
manager. Fun little fact about your uh
friend Christmas. Uh and is going to
give some some feedback on some online
financial advice that you come across on
Tik Tok. And uh this year we have the
proper naughty nice list to add the Tik
Toks to.
You can see there's a bit more space on
the naughty side. And so we'll be
keeping track of who goes on what list
here. And I made sure there's at least a
couple of of nice videos here because I
know you guys want me to just go through
the the bottom of the barrel stuff. But
but let me have this. Uh Santa needs to
restore some of his faith in and finance
content. But without further ado, let's
crisp these cringles. Guys, I'm
literally shaking right now and I got to
share this with somebody because I don't
think that people know that the average
person right now can make a lot of
money. We're talking about millions.
Okay. No, I don't have a course to sell.
No, this is not a sponsored video. Do
you remember how back in the day people
made their wealth because they bought a
lot of properties when properties were
like $5, right? Those days are
unattainable now. But our equivalent to
that is literally investing in the stock
market with what's going on with AI and
tech. Okay? Because if you're an adult
right now, you have a front seat to
what's going on and seeing how our world
is literally changing right before our
very eyes. You know how before people
would say, "Damn, if I invested $1,000
into Starbucks in the '90s, I'd be a
millionaire. If I invested $1,000 into
Amazon in the '90s, I'd be a
millionaire." This is our opportunity
for that. What is happening right now is
literally something that's like for a
lot of people, it's going to be once in
a lifetime. Look at just read is all I'm
saying. Okay, ladies, I know that stocks
are boring. I totally get it, right? But
like if you read something for 15
minutes and you invest $5,000 and you
see that $5,000 become $220,000,
>> all of a sudden that 15 minutes of
boring ass reading, it's not boring
anymore. Right now at a time where
people feel hopeless and they feel so
much despair and it's like the world is
against them there is a huge opportunity
for the average person to come out of
this with million.
So yes investing is great. It might be a
few companies that do really really well
with the AI situation we're in. Uh very
much misrepresenting the the opportunity
of investing. You're not going to find a
40x company with 50 minutes of reading.
Trust me, Santa has been trying his
best. [laughter] Now, in terms of
Starbucks and Amazon, you see this a lot
where people highlight a specific
example, even, you know, Bitcoin or
something like if you invested super
early, uh the amount of money that the
crazy returns you would see over the
long term. Uh but firstly uh when it
comes specifically to technological
revolutions like AI uh there's a lot of
research that seems to suggest they
don't actually tend to be that great of
a return source for investors. Uh tends
to be a lot of attrition in terms of
failed companies and investors lose a
lot of money basically fund the
revolution with their losses to an
extent. Um and you know when it comes to
leaders like Amazon yes we know their
leaders today but looking back and
assuming you could have picked them out
of the crowd is hindsight bias right?
Even if you pick out current leaders in
the space, that's no guarantee that
these companies will do well. Uh back
during the crisis, you had companies
like Netscape, uh the Globe.com,
companies that were perceived as leaders
in their category, and yet they still
failed and lost investors a bunch of
money. So, compare that to the current
AI situation. We right now have about
500 AI unicorns in the US, which are
companies with valuations over $1
billion. You just have to ask yourself
if there's going to be enough demand to
sustain all of these companies and what
sort of probability that gives you for
picking the winners in that crowd. So
yes, you could have gotten rich if you
had bought Amazon back in the '90s. But
ask yourself, how many people do you
know who did get rich by just buying
Amazon? And if the answer is not that
many, well, that kind of demonstrates
how likely it is to be making those sort
of bets and holding it through the ups
and downs of things like the dot crisis
because it's certainly not as common as
this video seems to suggest. So, look,
this person's young, but I am going to
have to put them on the naughty list for
suggesting that 15 minutes of research
can earn you 4,000% return. Also, I'm
sorry. This was about the exact same
time I took it off last time, but I'm
just getting beard hairs in my mouth
every word I say. Hey, Dad. I'm going to
start investing in the stock market. You
can't invest, Jimmy. You're 12. Go back
to playing Minecraft. Not true. Since I
follow Nick, I know that kids of any age
can invest as long as they open a
custodial brokerage account. I'll need
you to cosign, though. Does that mean I
have control over this money? You can
put money in, but once it's in there,
it's legally mine. And how much do you
think you'll earn from this thing? If I
invest my $200 monthly allowance into
index funds, I could have around 20K by
the TIME I'M 18. STOP FOLLOWING NICK.
HE'S GOING TO MAKE YOU RICHER than me.
Well, dad, maybe stop giving your son
200 bucks a month. How many how many
Robux does he need? I had an allowance
of like five bucks a week. And I know,
you know, obviously inflation and the
like, but I feel like 200 bucks is a lot
for for a 12-year-old. [laughter] So,
I'm usually pretty cautious around
content that that's geared towards
younger investors because yes, you know,
compounding interest is great. The
earlier you start, the better. Um, if
you have 200 bucks a month, awesome. Uh,
but most kids don't have that. And to
me, I'd much rather see them focus their
time and energy towards schooling, you
know, improving their skills and and
just developing, you know, having time
to be a kid. It's obviously great to
learn money skills early, like budgeting
and things like that. Uh, but, you know,
especially if you have a small
allowance, that's going to be outweighed
the moment you get your first real
paycheck, but overall, good information,
good TikTok. Uh, just quickly to add,
there are tax implications sometimes
with these types of custodial accounts.
So, you need to know the rules of where
you live. um the tax authority doesn't
want you investing money through your
child to avoid income taxes, right? So,
you got to be aware of when tax will be
recognized in their name versus your own
name. But, nonetheless, uh good Tik Tok.
Our first nice list edition. I I'll add
that there. Congratulations.
We did it. Next Tik Tok. You don't need
a job anymore. 50 grand a month is about
to be your new normal. And the reason I
know this is because I'm about to let
you in on one of the biggest secrets
that wealthy people have been
gatekeeping from you for the longest
time. You know what a trust fund is,
don't you? When you think of a trust
fund, you think of wealthy people. Uh
just quickly uh for those who don't know
what a trust fund is, trust is just a
legal entity, a structure that you set
up that holds money and assets in its
name for the benefit of a beneficiary
oftentimes like a child or or someone
who maybe can't control the money
themselves, but is is managed by a
trustee uh for the benefit of that
beneficiary. So, uh you can see it for
example if with inheritances that go
towards uh children who aren't old
enough to to manage the money themselves
or other sort of tax or state planning
purposes. And a trust fund is just a
trust that holds and invest money.
>> But did you know that it's not only
wealthy people that open trust funds?
People who are broke open trust funds
and they use them to become wealthy. And
now you're probably wondering how do
they do it?
>> I am [laughter] about to tell you. So,
make sure you save this video.
>> So, you open up a trust fund, which
anyone can do, and then you buy an asset
to put inside that trust fund. And if
you're thinking, well, I don't have an
asset to put inside the trust fund. What
people will do is they'll just go and
buy a life insurance policy to put
inside the trust fund. Life insurance
policies are very inexpensive and
they're accessible to almost anyone. You
can get in a million dollar policy for
anywhere between $100 to $200 a month.
So, if you were to buy that million-doll
policy and put it inside your trust
fund, that would bring your trust's
value to $1 million.
And then you do what the ultra rich do
all the time, which is borrow against
their assets. Because you put your life
insurance policy inside of your trust,
you can now borrow against the value of
that life insurance policy.
Now, if you borrow the money, you can do
what you want with it. But the smart
people, they use it to go invest and buy
businesses. They'll go out and buy small
franchises. They'll team up with other
investors and go buy things like
apartment buildings and other commercial
real estate. And once they start
collecting profits from those
businesses, they'll go back and they'll
pay off the loan that they used to
acquire those businesses in the first
place. And once they've paid off their
debts, they're now financially free and
can start building generational wealth
for themselves and their family. And if
you're wondering where I learned all of
that, it's in the book called Wealth
Secrets, which you can find in my bio.
If I were you, I would grab that book
and try and learn as much as possible
from it. Because when I started reading
it, it made me realize that becoming
wealthy really is just about what you
know.
>> So, I'm not a tax professional. But that
video was very misinformed in terms of
of trust structures and and how they
work. Broke people do not just open
trust funds uh to get rich. Trusts are
very expensive. They're they're are
administrative tax and legal fees
involved with them. Uh so already the
moment you open a trust, you're kind of
in the hole. Uh, and then buying a
policy to put in that trust doesn't just
give you a million dollars of benefit
that you can suddenly tap into. What you
can typically borrow against with a
whole life policy is what's called its
cash value, which is a portion of the
premium that you're paying into your
policy. But that cash value doesn't just
hit a million dollars the moment you buy
the policy. It starts off small and then
and then grows over time based on your
payments, right? So again, you're not
generating money out of nothing. And
even if you do borrow against any cash
value you have, you're still paying
interest on that. So even though you're
borrowing from yourself, you technically
aren't. You're actually still borrowing
the money from the insurance company
because there's no million dollars in
your trust to access, right? If you put
a policy in your trust, that trust
doesn't have any cash on hand to give
you. You have to reach out to the
insurance company. They lend you money
using that policy that they have in
house as collateral, but you're
effectively just taking a loan from the
insurance company. What you do see is
some wealthy people will buy whole life
policies and borrow against those
policies as a tax planning tool because
they're in the highest tax bracket and
even with the expenses of the premium
and the like it can still be worth it
when you're in the highest tax bracket
for you know reducing your your payable
taxes but for most people it's not worth
it. So very much misguided. Wealthy
people don't use whole life policies to
get rich. They are rich and then look to
use whole life policies for state or or
tax planning but that's it. It's not
some secret tool for going from zero to
$50,000 a month. I have no concept of
where that dollar amount's coming from.
So, look, I don't know if if maybe the
book maybe misled this guy. I haven't
heard of this book before. Or maybe he's
just misremembering the details of it.
But I do have to sadly put you on the
naughty list. But hey, if I'm wrong, if
you are making $50,000 a month with this
trust idea, uh just let me know and and
I'll be happy to correct and and put you
on the nice list. But uh otherwise,
let's move on. Next, Tik Tok. There's
literally no way that trading is not
going to work for you. [laughter]
>> I swear I I feel like Tik Toks are
getting more bold [laughter] with with
how they present their ideas or
concepts. You can't fail at trading. You
sure can. [laughter]
>> The only reason that people, you know,
say that it didn't work or they failed
is because they gave up. I'll say it
again. If I wanted to, I could teach
like a seven-year-old to trade. Trading
is not the [music] hard part. It's not
trading that you don't understand. The
psychology is the hard part. The
discipline is the hard part. The
motivation, the consistency, those are
the things that make people fail. Not
the actual [music] skill of trading. The
actual skill of trading is honestly just
not that difficult to understand.
[music] And like I said before, that's
like 5% of being an actual trader. The
rest is all the psychology. All that to
say, keep doing [music] it. It's going
to end up working out. You just need to
make sure you get discipline and
consistency and all that, you know,
under control. and [music] the rest is a
piece of cake. Literally,
>> that's what I've been saying. That's
consistency is the key. You don't want
to let your psychology psych you out.
That's why whenever I use the plain
bagel trading pattern, [music] patented
by the way, we're always betting on red.
Every time it's red only
or is it black?
Wait a minute. So, psychology matters
with investing. Definitely plays a role
with investment returns. There's a very
popular series of studies called the
Dowbar studies that found that most
equity investors underperform the
market. Not because of fees or even
strategy, but one of the top factors is
actually their well in addition to lack
of capital um is their psychology,
right? Chasing returns, selling out of
positions early and and buying into and
chasing returns in other funds um that
really hampers their performance rather
than just focusing on the long term. So
it does matter and behavioral economics
is a really fascinating field when it
comes to trading. This kind of stuff is
just highlighted as an out right for for
people who promise high returns but then
don't see people able to achieve that
especially because half these people are
selling trading courses that are
supposedly so easy you can just automate
the process or you know anyone can do
it. uh then psychology shouldn't really
matter if it's like mathematical, right?
If I see a stock drop below a resistance
line, if the pattern is as simple as
they highlight, then there's not much
emotion to be had, right? Because I'm
just following the steps you told me to
follow. But yeah, to be clear, trading
does not work for the vast majority of
people. There are plenty of papers to
highlight that. And the people who say
otherwise, vast majority of the time,
they have some interest in getting you
to trade, right? Whether it be they're
selling a course or a Discord signals
group or whatever. Um, in fact, you
know, if we just go on Tik Tok and
search trading, you can see how many of
the top videos are courses, right? Here,
subscription and affiliate links,
trading course or mentorship of some
sort. Again, subscription and promotion,
selling a trading program.
So far, five out of five. [laughter] So,
if you just look at top results for
trading, it's all this content, right,
of people talking about their their
gains, their wins, glorifying this day
trading life and process to try and get
you to to buy into that lifestyle
they're selling despite there not being
much merit oftent times to to the course
or the pattern they're using. So, you
really got to be cautious with
influencers and people you follow
online, including myself. You know, be
aware of people's conflicts of interest.
Even I, you know, I work in the
industry. I have a conflict of interest
as well. And you need to be aware of
that so that you can frame the
information, the details you get from
them, right? It's not to say that anyone
who sells a course or whatever suddenly
you can't trust anything they say, but
that information is important to what
they do say, right? If they start
telling you, oh, you can make millions
of dollars trading, you're going to look
at that information differently if you
also know they sell a trading course,
right? So, so very important to to be
aware of that kind of stuff.
>> Here's the one financial rule I will
always always follow every single time I
get paid, and that is I will always pay
myself first. Every time a paycheck hits
my account, it automatically takes 50%,
puts it into my investments. That is me
paying my future self. After that,
$1,000 goes straight into my credit card
fund, which is going to be used to pay
off my monthly credit card statement.
That's it. As someone who was a mega
spender before, this was the only way
that helped me save money for the future
me while still not feeling guilty about
spending money that I need to spend.
Because before I would just let my
paycheck hit my account, spend it all
and then see collect some coins of what
I can save, which was two bucks, five
bucks here and there. Not a lot. Not
great for wealth building. So, pay
myself first is the only rule that I
will ever follow.
>> All right, good Tik Tok. Another another
nice little addition. We're We're doing
it, guys. We're healing. You know, I see
some comments about it being unrealistic
to put aside half your salary, but the
underlying practice is a solid one,
right? I I understand not everyone can
afford to pay themselves first when
you're living paycheck to paycheck. So,
you know, very clear distinction, but
this person is just sharing their own
experience. A lot of people find this
very helpful, this idea of paying
yourself first where you put this fixed
expense for your investments aside first
thing when you get your paycheck so that
as you get towards the end of your
paycheck period, you're adjusting your
discretionary spending rather than your
investments to whatever you have left
over. When it comes to anything finance
or budgeting related, automation is your
best friend. Uh people only have certain
amount of mental bandwidth for dealing
with all of life's stresses and as that
mental bandwidth gets taken up from
other stuff, it can be hard to dedicate
mental efforts towards your your
finances and your budgeting, right? It's
why you can see people who are very well
educated and very fiscally responsible
sort of fall to bad financial habits
when they're stressed out at work or or
have a late night or things like that
because they just don't have the mental
bandwidth in that moment. It's why
people can make really severe mistakes
even with sort of a good foundation. So
good tactic obviously you need to know
how much you can afford to put aside.
You don't want to put yourself in a bad
situation by doing so when you say first
start. But when stuff like this becomes
more habitual, it's more likely again
that you'll stay with it consistently
and and see that progression over time.
I told you to buy this stock 5 weeks ago
when it was just 5 and now it's sitting
at [music] $1.80. That's a 36 times
return. And some of my followers
actually made that move. And once again,
I'm not selling a course or charging for
anything. Everything I share is
completely free. [music] I just post
undervalued penny stocks with massive
upside potential. And right now, I found
another one that shows all the signs I
look for. It's a Canadian oil company
called Altea Energy.
>> Uhoh. [laughter]
Canadian uh over-the-counter micro crap
stock. Probably a paid promotion. I had
a video a while ago where I I talked
about this trend of junior mining or
exploration energy and and mining
companies in Canada paying creators
online to promote their stock with these
types of videos. Yeah, it's it's sadly
become a a bit of a trend. Normally, you
can find a press release about their
marketing, but let me see. Wait. So, the
stock has a ceased trade order and is in
default
as of the end of last year, as of
December 2024. So, this guy's just
actively promoting a company on the
verge of being shut down. Yeah, that's
uh I wouldn't recommend it.
>> The fastest way to change your financial
future in 2025 isn't buying Bitcoin.
>> Oh, no.
I'm just realizing now that whole thing
was AI.
>> They ask you how you are and you just
have to say that you're fine when you're
not really fine.
>> That's crazy. That kind of leads me to
wonder if the companies behind this type
of content. Honestly, it wouldn't
surprise me at this point. Like there's
a lot of really nefarious and sketchy
marketing happening with with really
small companies and just no very little
regulatory action going against it. So,
you have to be so careful. I've never
been got by a by an AI video like that.
That's Wow, that's embarrassing.
[laughter] It's not even that good. In
hindsight, it's it's not even that good.
You can see around like the eyes and the
mouth. Like, it's all very unnatural.
But, uh, if that's not proof to take
everything you hear online with with a
grain of salt. Um, yeah. Yikes.
Let's move on. Try try to forget that
happened. Most people don't know this,
but Chat GBT is a genius when it comes
to trading stocks. Here are 10 quickfire
Chat GBT prompts to help you make money
from the stock market. Number one,
market research and trend analysis.
Analyze the current trends in the stock
market, focusing on your sector or
stock. Identify any emerging patterns
and suggest potential investment
opportunities. Consider recent earnings
reports and industry news in your
analysis. Number two, portfolio
diversification. Given a portfolio with
a mix of your current sectors or stocks,
suggest strategies to diversify further
while minimizing risk. Include potential
sectors to explore and specific stocks
to consider. Number three, an AI powered
stock screener. Help me build an AI
powered
>> All right, you get the idea. the there's
10 kind of AI prompts for improving the
investment process. And listen, I
actually use AI when searching for
different financial details. I don't
often rely on on what it tells me, but
it sources some of the details. So, um
you know, if I'm looking for a very
niche or specific detail, um I find it's
helpful to use AI to try and track the
the source to find that information. Uh
but it's important to recognize that
chatbt is not a judgment model. when you
ask Chachi BT to analyze something, it's
not going through and and calculating,
you know, financial models, um, even
really researching different reports,
especially because most of them are
going to be paywalled or, you know,
whatever. It is simply predicting what
someone given the data points it has,
would likely reply to the question you
asked it or or the prompt you gave it.
That's not to say you can't use AI to
improve your research process. uh some
of these prompts might work but uh you
know it's not really meant for for this
type of activity and so you don't want
to put undo weight on its on its output
if it's not really built for that. I
know actually early on when Chach was
first launched, there was a a portfolio,
the GBT portfolio that claimed to be
beating the S&P 500. And there are now
services that let you invest in
portfolios picked by these AI models.
And you can see that they post a
supposed average return that beats the
market again. But really, if you look at
each individual uh AI system, the
results are just all over the place,
right? you have uh sometimes it
outperforms the S&P 500 over that time
period. Sometimes it's severely
underperforming the the S&P 500. So
looking at these results, a there it's
not really a standardized return, so you
got to be, you know, cautious of that.
Uh but B, it just kind of paints to me a
randomized picture. Yes, in this period,
the average seems to be doing better
than than the S&P 500, but you're
talking about a couple of years of of
potentially just random results. Uh any
random set could give you that sort of
output. So AI can be a handy tool. Uh
some of these prompts might work uh to
an extent, but just be aware of of what
you're getting. Right? This is basically
using the internet to give you a summary
of what the internet would try to reply
to to your answer. Uh that's not always
going to be the internet's not always
wellinformed on on uh you know where to
invest money. Definitely wouldn't
suggest investing based on what chatbt
highlights. So yeah, that's the video.
We have our our list now. Put the beard
back on for the for the outro. Uh got to
get some use out of it. Yeah. Uh couple
couple nice on there, but overall just
uh still some work to be done. That's
okay. We always have 2026, right? We
always have next year. Let me know in
the comments down below what your
favorite uh Tik Tok was, your favorite
takeaways, and any other content you'd
like me to uh review in the future.
Thanks again for watching. I'm taking
this off. It's way too hot.
See you in the next one. [laughter]
I got to go to the office right after
this and pretend like I wasn't just
dressed up like Santa Claus.